Guide to the Charles Owen Rice Papers, 1894-2005 AIS.1976.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- FBI Files, 1947-1986; V.
  - Files Obtained by Father Rice, 1.
    - File Documents, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - File Documents, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - File Documents, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - File Documents, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - File Documents, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - File Documents, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - File Documents, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - File Documents, 1974-1976 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Files Obtained by Researchers, 2.
    This subseries, created in July 2011, contains FBI files regarding Father Rice which were obtained by researcher Steve Rosswurm in 2009. These files include portions that were omitted from the records obtained by Father Rice's 1977 FOIA request. Also, these files have been maintained in their original order, reflecting the origin of the records as either the FBI headquarters or Pittsburgh field office.
    - File Documents and Correlation Summary, FBI Headquarters, 1947-1972 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1941-1966 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1966-1967 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 4-5)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1969-1970 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1971-1972 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - File Documents, FBI Pittsburgh Field Office, 1972-1976 (Box 51, Folder 3)
- Holy Rosary School, 1969-1974; VI.
  Series VI contains materials related to Father Rice's time as Pastor of the Holy Rosary School in the Homewood section of Pittsburgh. Rice took over the school in 1966, and by 1968, he had developed a new program that he believed suited the community's children better. The program consisted of non-traditional approaches to Catholic school education where the principal was not catholic, the students did not have to wear uniforms, and there was a general sense of independence for the students. This series contains funding proposals, newsclippings, yearbooks, and letters to Father Rice from school children (1969-1974).
  - Children's Letters, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - General, 1971-1974 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - General, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Proposals for Funding, 1969-1972 (Box 35, Folder 16-17)
- Manuscripts and Publications, 1927-2002; VII.
  Series VII contains manuscripts, articles, pamphlets, book reviews, sermons, and newspaper columns from the Pittsburgh Catholic. This series is divided into two subseries. The first is a collection of general manuscripts and publications, arranged alphabetically by subject. The second is material relating to Rice's Pittsburgh Catholic column, and is arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically.
  - General Material, 1.
    - Articles about Charles Owen Rice, 1950-1986 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Books Reviews, by and of Charles Owen Rice, 1934-1937 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Books Reviews, by and of Charles Owen Rice, 1949-1957 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Books Reviews, by and of Charles Owen Rice, 1972-1974 and undated (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - The Catholic Bulletin, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - The Catholic Bulletin, Correspondence, 1975-1983 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Duquesne Monthly, 1927-1929 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - "The Football Abuse", 1935 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Irish Artists, 1934 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Local 590 News, 1961-1978 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Manuscripts, 1936-1971 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Pamphlets, 1937-1946 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Pittsburgh's Hospitality House Information, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Psychology Lecture at Mt. Mercy College, Tests, Reaction Studies, undated (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Published Articles with Related Correspondence, 1933-1973 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Sermons, 1935-1976 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished Articles by Father Rice, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Catholic, 2.
    - Columns, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Columns, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Columns, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Columns, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Columns, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Columns, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Columns, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Columns, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Columns, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Columns, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Columns, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Columns, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Columns, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Columns, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Columns, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Columns, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Columns, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Columns, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Columns, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Columns, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Columns, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Columns, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Columns, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Columns, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Columns, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Columns, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Columns, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Columns, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Columns, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Columns, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Columns, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Columns, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Columns, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Columns, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Columns, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Columns, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Columns, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Columns, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Columns, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Columns, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Columns, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Columns, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Columns, 2000 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Columns, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Columns, 2002 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Columns, Ideas, undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Drafts, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Drafts, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Drafts, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Drafts, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Drafts, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Drafts, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Drafts, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Drafts, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Drafts, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Drafts, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Drafts, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Drafts, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Drafts, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Drafts, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Drafts, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Drafts, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Drafts, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Drafts, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Drafts, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Drafts, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Drafts, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Drafts, 2001-2002 (Box 40, Folder 2)
- Autobiographical Material, 1956-1997; VIII.
  Series VIII contains material that Father Rice compiled to construct his autobiography. The series includes drafts of his autobiography, as well as material he used for reference. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Autobiography, "Outline of Possible Book", 1970 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Autobiography, "Outline of Possible Book", undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Autobiography, "Did Not Use" Book Section, 1970 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Autobiography, "Continuums for Chapter One", undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Autobiography, "Continuums for Chapter One", undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Autobiography, "Association of Catholic Trade Unionists" and other text fragments, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Autobiography, "War with the Communists", 1989 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Autobiography, untitled book section drafts, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Autobiography, untitled miscellaneous book draft text, undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Autobiography, untitled miscellaneous book draft text, undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Autobiography, untitled miscellaneous book draft text, undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Autobiography, untitled miscellaneous book draft text, undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Autobiography, untitled miscellaneous book draft text, undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Autobiography, untitled miscellaneous book draft text, undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Autobiography, Correspondence, 1966-1993 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Awards, Proclamations and Congratulations, 1966-1994 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Civil Rights Notebook, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Column, Pittsburgh Post-Gazette Round Table, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Commencement Address, Indiana University of Pennsylvania, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Commencement Address, St. Vincent College, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Interview Transcript, Jim Garvey, undated (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Interview Transcript, Kevin McNulty, 1980-1989 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Interview Transcript, Mark Mullen, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Interview Transcript, Bud and Ruth Schultz, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Interview Transcript, University of Notre Dame, 1977-1978 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Interview Transcript, University of Notre Dame, 1977-1978 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Interview Transcript, James A. Young, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Oral History Interview Transcript, Robert L. Anderson, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Philanthropic Donation Cards, 1983-1999 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Prayer, AFL-CIO Convention, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Published Articles and Related Correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Sermons, High School Graduations, 1956-1972 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Sermons, Labor Day, 1956, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Sermons, Passion, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Short Biographies, 1964-1998 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Speech, "Are You For Sale?", 1990 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Speech, Pennsylvania Personnel and Guidance Association, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Speech, "The US Economy and Social Justice", 1985 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Speeches, 1960-1961 (Box 41, Folder 12)
- Biographical Material, 1950-2005; IX.
  Series IX contains biographical materials written about Father Rice, primarily Charles McCollester's Fighter With a Heart and Patrick J. McGeever's Apostle of Contradiction. It includes drafts of and correspondence regarding these publications, as well as various newspaper articles about Rice. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Articles, 1950-1979 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Articles, 1980-1989 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1980-1989 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Articles, 1990-2005 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Articles, undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With a Heart," Drafts- First, undated (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," Drafts-Second, undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," Drafts-Third, undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," General Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," McCollester Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," McCollester Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," McCollester Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," Promotional Events, 1996-1997 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - McCollester, Charles, "Fighter With A Heart," Reviews and Promotional Material, 1996-1998 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," Draft, undated (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," Draft, undated (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," Draft, undated (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," General Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," McGeever Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," McGeever Correspondence, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," McGeever Correspondence, 1985-1994 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - McGeever, Patrick J., "Apostle of Contradiction," Reviews and Promotional Material, 1989-1997 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Nintieth Birthday Celebration, 1998 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Ordination Anniversary, 45th, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Ordination Anniversary, 50th, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Family Papers, 1934-1947; X.
  Series X contains material on Father Rice's family, most notably correspondence with his brother Patrick Rice. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Army Appointment of Patrick Rice, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Copy of Will of Patrick Rice, 1934, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Patrick Rice, 1937-1946 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Patrick Rice, 1944 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Patrick Rice, 1945 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Patrick Rice, 1946 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence with Patrick Rice, undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1880s-2004; XI.
  Series XI contains photographs of Father Rice, primarily documenting his career as a labor and civil rights activist. Also included are photos of the Rice family, dating back to the 1880s. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically. Additional oversize material at the end of the series is also arranged alphabetically.
  - Addressing steel workers in front of Youngstown Steel and Tube, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Bishop John Wright, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Caricature, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Church Photos, 1990s (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Duquesne University Class Photo, 1930 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Family Photos, 1880s-1960s and undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Family Photos, 1880s-1960s and undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Family Photos, 1880s-1960s and undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Father Rice and Gerry Adams, c. 1980s (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Jesse Jackson Candidacy, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Personal Photos, ca. 1930s (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Photos for a 1986 Interview, 1950s-1980s (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Photos from a 1988 Interview (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Photos for a 1987 Pittsburgh Catholic Article, 1950s-1960s (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Pittsburgh Strikes, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - "Reds and Workers", 1941-1959 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - St. Patrick's Day, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Seventieth Ordainment Anniversary, 2004 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Swearing-In to the Allegheny County Prison Board, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Trip to St. Louis, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - 1920s (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - 1930s (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - 1940s (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - 1950s (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - 1960s (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - 1970s (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - 1980s (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - 1990s (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - March Down 5th Avenue, Pittsburgh, 1940s (Oversize 1)
  - Pencil Portrait of Father Rice, 1999 (Oversize 2)
  - Radio Broadcast Photos, 1960s (Oversize 3)
  - Radio Interview Photo, 1967 (Oversize 4)
- Audio Tapes, 1945-1975; XII.
  Series XII contains audio tapes of interviews, services, banquets, sermons, and radio broadcasts on various subjects including abortion, labor relations, Vietnam, and Ireland. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - House of Hospitality - Father Rice interview by John Trent, 1945 (Box 44, Reel 1)
  - Rice Radio Broadcast - John J. Wright, 1959 (Box 44, Reel 2)
  - For The Record, KDKA Radio - Birth Control, January 5, 1959 (Box 44, Reel 3)
  - Silver Jubilee Mass and Banquet, June 17, 1959 (Box 44, Reel 4)
  - Mass, Soldiers and Sailors, Oakland, August 4, 1959 (Box 44, Reel 5)
  - Speech - Steel Strike, 1959 (Box 44, Reel 6)
  - Literary Varieties, hosted by Rice - Dr. Alan Markman, February 23, 1960 (Box 44, Reel 7)
  - For the Record, KDKA Radio - Regulated Birth and Catholic Church, March 17, 1960 (Box 44, Reel 8)
  - Tempered in Steel - Memorial to Philip Murray, 1962 (Box 45, Reel 9)
  - Interviews about Philip Murray, 1962 (Box 45, Reel 10)
  - WWSW Radio - Chesterton, Abortion, Carmichael's, January 14, 1962; December 2, 1962; December 9, 1962 (Box 45, Reel 11)
  - Testimonial Dinner for Rice Investiture as Domestic Prelate, WJPA Radio, March 18, 1964 (Box 45, Reel 12-15)
  - Radio Broadcast - Jewish/Christian Relations, March 22, 1964 (Box 45, Reel 16)
  - Msgr. Rice: The Boldest Irishman, March 29, 1964 (Box 46, Reel 17)
  - Radio Broadcast - God is Dead, June 19, 1966 (Box 46, Reel 18)
  - Priests' Retreat, Atlanta - Moral responsibility of Priests, 1967 (Box 46, Reel 19)
  - Speech - Anti-war Rally, New York, 1967 (Box 46, Reel 20)
  - Radio Broadcast - Father Tom Reilly and the Hill District, April 2, 1967 (Box 46, Reel 21)
  - Contact, KDKA Radio - March for Peace in New York and San Francisco, April 20, 1967 (Box 46, Reel 22)
  - Radio Broadcast - Jack Deedy, Pittsburgh Catholic, April 23, 1967 (Box 46, Reel 23)
  - Not Just Sunday, KDKA Radio - Role of television news, April 21, 1968 (Box 46, Reel 24)
  - Radio Broadcast - Vicar, Holy Rosary's dog, April 28, 1968 (Box 46, Reel 25)
  - Radio Broadcast, November 17, 1968 (Box 46, Reel 26)
  - Radio Broadcast, April 21, 1969; February 9, 1969; February 16, 1969 (Box 47, Reel 27)
  - Radio Broadcast - WWSW Radio, March 2, 1969; March 9, 1969 (Box 47, Reel 28)
  - John Cardinal Wright, Assignment: The Vatican, hosted by Rice, June 13, 1969 (Box 47, Reel 29)
  - Radio Broadcast, WJAS Radio, March 8, 1970; March 15, 1970 (Box 47, Reel 30-33)
  - Advertisement for The Msgr. Rice Show, WJAS (Announcer: Ted Payne), March 23, 1970 (Box 47, Reel 34)
  - Radio Broadcast, WWSW Radio, Irish Problem, July 5, 12, and 19, 1970 (Box 47, Reel 35)
  - Radio Broadcast, WWSW Radio, Christmas Thoughts, December 18, 1972 (Box 48, Reel 36)
  - Radio Broadcast, no date (Box 48, Reel 37)
  - Radio Broadcast, Irish Hunger Strike, no date (Box 48, Reel 39)
  - Radio Broadcast, WWSW Radio, Holy Rosary School, John Mosley, no date (Box 48, Reel 40)
  - Radio Broadcast, English Language and How it Changes, no date (Box 48, Reel 41)
  - Radio Broadcast, WWSW Radio, no date (Box 48, Reel 42)
  - Radio Broadcast, White/Black Relations, no date (Box 48, Reel 38)
  - Speech - Labor, no date (Box 48, Reel 43)
  - Vatican Mass in Latin, no date (Box 48, Reel 44-45)
  - Vatican Mass in Latin, no date (Box 49, Reel 46)
  - Radio Broadcast - John Mosley, principal of Holy Rosary School, no date (Box 49, Reel 47)
  - Convent dedication by Bishop Wright, no date (Box 49, Reel 48)
  - Radio Broadcast, WWSW Radio, My Lai, Vietnam Massacre, no date (Box 49, Reel 49)
  - Radio Broadcast, WJAS Radio, April 13, 1969; June 30, 1969 (Box 49, Reel 50)
  - Radio Broadcast, WJAS Radio, July 22, 1969 (Box 49, Reel 51)
  - Portrait of Msgr. Rice: A Man of The People, WWSW Radio, no date (Box 49, Reel 52)
  - Radio Broadcast, WWSW Radio, Interview with Bouie Haden, July 14, 1974 (Box 49, Reel 53)
  - Eulogy for Bouie Haden by Rice, August 3, 1974 (Box 49, Reel 54)
  - Concerning Charles Owen Rice, 1974 (Box 49, Reel 55)
  - "The Voice of Ireland," Irish News and Information Service, St. Paul, Minnesota, October, 1974; February and March, 1975 (Box 49, Reel 56-58)
  - House of Hospitality, audiodisc, November 22, 1945 (Box 49, Reel 59)
  - Radio Broadcast, WWSW Christmas Show, 1975 (Box 49, Reel 60)
  - Dictations of Correspondence, undated (Box 49, Reel 61)
  - Rice's Autobiography, undated (Box 49, Reel 62)